[The Old Story of Yu Hong]
[Episode 4]
Liu Juan, a police officer
at Yuhong Square Police Station,
brought a child to the office
for an overnight stay during her shift.
For that, she is given
a disciplinary warning
and disqualified from the this year's
Outstanding Police Officer
selection.
This is
the di-division's decision.
That child isn't even mine.
Why am I being punished?
I gave an explanation on your behalf,
but the higher-ups said
that since you are the child's
temporary guardian,
looking after her
is a personal matter of yours.
Did I ask to be her temporary guardian?
If I were out on patrol,
saw an unattended child,
and brought them back,
would I be punished?
What's with you?
Nothing. I just...
Have some water.
T-Take a sip.
Just an old ailment.
-Look at you.
-Any loud noise
makes my head start pounding.
It's okay. I'll be fine
after a short rest.
See, what a mess.
How about...
you get back to your work?
Go do your thing.
I'll get going then.
What should be done about this, huh?
[Vitamin C]
Complete shambles.
Sit somewhere else.
Stop hogging my seat and scribbling.
This is you.
This is me.
This is a snowman.
What's that about now?
All that mumbling,
and I didn't understand a word.
This is you.
Who's this? Me?
And what's this thing?
A snowman?
You're a little girl from the south.
Have you even seen a snowman?
She's actually a good painter.
It's all over.
My transfer to the division fell through.
I won't get a pay raise either.
When will I ever save enough money
for my younger brother's wedding?
Come on. I'm taking you out.
Hurry. Quick.
Get up already.
Or you'll be late for work.
Get a move on.
Sure.
Okay.
He had too...
too much to drink last night, huh?
Going out, aren't you?
How about I give you a ride?
This motorcycle.
The smaller key's for the lock.
Hand me the lock.
Hold the throttle grip
as you step on that lever.
-This lever?
-Step on it. Yes, that's the one.
Both actions at once.
Simultaneously.
Get on.
Hold on tight.
Chief,
you must give me an explanation today.
That man froze to death.
Why am I being punished?
Did I have the wind blow,
or did I make it snow?
This is nothing personal against you.
The division meant
for this decision as a warning.
Any officer would've been
treated the same.
How is it nothing personal against me?
The notice has made it perfectly clear:
a disciplinary warning to me
for looking after
a child while I was on duty.
Look at her.
Look at her little face.
How could she possibly be my child?
See, she has a round face,
while mine is long.
She's got prominent double eyelids,
while mine are hidden.
She has a rounded nose tip,
while I have a flat nose bridge.
You...
Why is it so cold in your office?
The kid is catching a cold.
The division is tight on funds.
Blow your nose. Blow hard.
Sun Zheng is a real bastard.
After we divorced so many years ago,
he dumped the child of his mistress
here with me
without a single word.
Did I cross or mess with anyone?
This girl is not my daughter.
But I couldn't have left her alone
on the streets
and let her freeze to death, right?
Even stray cats and dogs
shouldn't be ignored
in such cold weather.
I didn't bend the rules
for personal ends, did I?
I was obviously doing a good deed.
Besides...
I was on the night shift,
and I kept her at the station.
It didn't get in the way of my patrol.
I was supposed to patrol every two hours.
Zhao Changyou froze to death at 10:00,
right?
When I was patrolling and spotted him
at 11:00,
he had already turned into a block of ice.
Even doctors who work miracles
couldn't have helped
and brought him back to life.
Why issue a public criticism against me?
Don't get all worked up.
I'm not worked up.
I just feel wronged.
Look,
I'm a woman of a certain age,
single and divorced.
This four-year-old kid coming
from nowhere isn't even related to me,
yet she just became a burden
on my shoulders.
B-But instead of helping me out
and taking care
of the child, the station made me
take the blame when trouble occurred.
Is there any sense of human decency
or class solidarity?
Besides, this kid
has no family here.
Whenever she opens
her mouth,
it's total gibberish.
Hello, I'm Qianqian.
I'm four years old.
Did you hear that?
Sh-She speaks Cantonese.
D-Do you understand a word of it?
Look at her.
What will happen if she gets sick
when nobody is around?
How's that going to work?
Who should be responsible?
Chief, if you really think
that I handled personal matters
during work hours,
how about this—
from today on, whenever I'm on duty,
I'll send the child
to your place.
Just ask your wife
to look after her for a while, okay?
Juan,
the division has treated you well
over these years, right?
Years ago, you went to Guangzhou
and caused a huge mess there.
I personally talked
with the local police station,
so they let you off.
When that incident of yours was reported
to the municipal bureau, every division
officer put in a good word for you.
Only by being transferred
from the division to this station
did you manage to keep your job.
You remember it, don't you?
What are you trying to say?
As you know,
since the restructuring
of state-owned enterprises
in Tiecheng started,
there have been waves of laid-off workers.
Every division and station in the city
is walking on eggshells,
fearing what may happen.
You guys were just unlucky.
A man died a hundred meters
away from your station.
If his family makes a big fuss over it,
not only your station,
but also the entire division will suffer.
This public criticism
isn't a reprimand aimed at you.
It's only to pacify
the family of the deceased.
Well then...
It's just a minor public criticism.
An administrative penalty
won't affect your promotion.
Juan, you're a veteran officer.
Just take the blame for the division
this time.
Consider it a way to return the favor,
okay?
Will it really not affect my promotion?
Absolutely not.
Then when will I be transferred back?
Well, um...
I need to use the restroom now.
I'm getting old. Can't hold it in.
What an adorable little girl.
[Office for Political Affairs]
Are you feeling cold?
Look, your nose has been running all day.
Blow harder.
The phone is ringing.
Is your hat too light for winter?
What is it that's so urgent?
Should I answer the phone?
I should?
This is your idea.
I'll answer it then.
Hello.
Is Chief Zhang there?
He's gone to the restroom,
saying that he's getting old
and can't hold it in.
Tell me if anything has come up.
I'll pass the message to him.
I'm He Liang from the Second CIU
of the Yingjin Municipal Bureau.
We've been working on a case of smuggling
wildlife products for over six months.
Recently, we just got a lead
and tracked down one of the suspects.
He lives in your jurisdiction.
So we'd like to ask for
your division's help
to get this person under control.
We'll arrive shortly.
Okay. Just give me
the name and address
of the suspect.
The name is Zhao Changyou.
As for the address... Let me check.
No need for that.
I know where he is.
Really?
Could you have him under control now?
Not a problem. You just come over.
This man's completely under control now.
Come straight to our place
after you get off the train.
You'll be just in time
to see his body thaw.
Listen, shortly after
Zhao Changyou froze to death,
the police came looking for him.
Suspicious, isn't it?
I thought he was just a drunkard.
Who would've known he was also
a suspect in a smuggling case?
Then he probably didn't freeze to death.
Suppose he was murdered
and dumped in the stadium,
then I would be off the hook,
right?
Let's go.
Stand up.
Time to get to work
and find clues.
You're so heavy.
Mind your steps.
Keep this in mind:
in this world,
there's no such thing as a ghost or god.
Living people are the scary ones.
What's to fear about the dead?
Think about it.
If a dead person really became a ghost,
decided to scare you,
and frightened you to death,
then you would turn into a ghost yourself.
Both ending up in the same place,
you would get to beat him up. Understood?
So don't be afraid when we're in there.
Just stand next to me. Alright?
[Police Badge]
This represents righteousness.
Keep it with you.
All spirits will be deterred.
Let's go.
[Specimen name: Meningeal tissue]
The kid has some real guts.
She probably
has no idea what's in that jar.
She knows, obviously.
Then she may
attend medical school and get in
the same profession as you.
Sounds viable.
I'm telling you,
she must have a certain gift
since she's not afraid at all.
What did the autopsy reveal?
Before this man froze to death,
he had quite a meal.
What did he eat?
From his stomach,
we found undigested
bean sprouts, cabbage, peanuts,
jellyfish with scallions,
twice-cooked pork,
and dumplings
filled with pickled cabbage.
This means he had just enjoyed a big meal.
He probably ate near the square.
I have an inquiry.
I'm from Yuhong Police Station.
Have you seen this man?
No, never.
No.
Take a look at it too, please.
Does he seem familiar to you?
No, we've never seen this guy.
In addition,
his blood alcohol level
was insanely high.
He must have drunk
at least two catties of liquor.
Then he definitely didn't eat alone.
[Yuhong Stadium] [Funeral Store]
[Yuhong Subdistrict]
I remember
when I found him,
there was a cigarette in his mouth.
But on his body,
we didn't find cigarette cases, lighters,
or matches.
None of those.
[Gang's Diner]
[Please head to the second floor]
That means there was
someone else at the scene.
You busy?
Hello.
I'm an officer of Yuhong Police Station.
I'd like to ask you about someone.
Have you seen this person?
He looks a bit familiar.
Really?
Yes.
I recall it.
This man ate here a few days ago.
Did he really?
He absolutely did.
This little diner of mine
usually receives
taxi drivers, delivery guys, and such.
In most cases, they just order
rice with toppings or fried noodles.
Those are highly affordable.
But that day, this man
and his fellow ordered...
several dishes, anyway.
I got so busy with that.
Jellyfish ran out,
so I had to get some from Si next door.
His fellow? So this man wasn't here alone?
There was another man.
He was quite tall
and slender,
with a moustache.
Looked like he was
in his twenties,
or maybe thirties.
How old exactly?
Twenty to thirty.
Did they drink?
Oh my.
The two of them drank a lot.
How much exactly?
Just a lot.
When did they leave?
Late at night.
How come you just
can't give me a straight answer?
Oh, come on.
H-How could I be sure
about so many details?
I'm the only staffer in this diner.
I have to do everything—
washing, cooking, chopping, and cleaning.
How am I supposed to keep track
of every customer?
Did they leave together?
Probably.
What did I...
What did I tell you?
Stop it.
I did the investigation myself.
Fine.
What does it have to do
with the Yellow and the Green Immortal?
Who do you think this person is?
I've asked around in the neighborhood.
Only this diner owner said
he had seen him.
But...
he couldn't describe
this man's looks accurately.
Everything's so vague.
No first name. No last name.
How am I supposed to find him out?
May I speak my opinion?
Just go ahead
and say whatever you have to say.
Didn't you tell me to stop?
Quick. Speak up.
I know a way
to let you see what this man looks like.
How?
By making the Yellow Immortal
take a picture of him?
You want to see his face or not?
Speak your mind already.